

# **Faruk Dube**

# **Doctoral Student**

## **My Contact**

farukmeddie@gmail.com

+46 76 409 28 47

Kungsgatan 66 Å, Uppsala

in Faruk Dube

### **Education**

- Uppsala University, Sweden, 2016-2018
  Masters of Medical Science in Infection
  Biology, Biological and Biomedical Sciences
- Makerere University, Uganda, 2009-2012
  Bachelor of Science in Biomedical
  Laboratory Technology

## Wet lab skills

- PCR-based techniques
- ELISA
- Bacterial, Viral, fungal and C. elegans culture
- DNA/RNA handling
- Sequencing library preparation

## **Computer skills**

- NGS data analysis (Genome and Transcritpome)
- Pipeline building with Nextflow
- Data wrangling and visualisation
- Statistics
- Programming in R and Python
- Unix
- Git
- Illustration in Inkscape

# Language

- Luganda (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Swedish (Beginner Intermediate)
- Swahili (Intermediate)

#### **About Me**

An infection biologist interested in utilizing both lab work and computational resources to solve biological/medical problems. I have previously worked with viruses, fungi, bacteria, and now parasites. Currently, I am a doctoral student utilizing both wet-lab and bioinformatics techniques to determine why parasites are resistant to available drugs.

## **Professional Experience**

PhD candidate | Swedish University of Agricultural Science 2019/10 - Present

#### Activities:

- Thesis "Ivermectin-induced gene expression changes in adult Parascaris univalens and Caenorhabditis elegans- a comparative approach to understand and control threatening anthelmintic resistance"
- Worm culture and drug exposure experiments
- RNA handling
- Primer design and RT-qPCR
- Transcriptomic data analysis and visualisation
- Manuscript writing
- · Two scientific studies published

#### Research Engineer | National Veterinary Institute 2018/07 - 2019/10

Key responsibilities:

- Bacteria and Fungi culture and DNA handling
- · DNA library preparation, sequencing, genome analysis
- Building NGS data analysis pipelines
- Provide bioinformatics support to different projects
- · One scientific study published

#### Laboratory Technologist | Makerere university-Walter Reed Project 2013/04 - 2016/08

- Key responsibilities:
- Virus culturing
- Sample and RNA/DNA handling
- PCR- and ELISA-based assays
- · Training interns

## **Awards**

2022 Travel grant-SLU

2022 Travel grant-Foundation Alfa Laval AB's (AB Separators) fund

2021 Travel grant - SLU

2020 Stiftelsen Gösta och Sonja Engströms fond

2016 Swedish Institute Study Scholarship for a two-year masters studies in Sweden